Sound Recordings of Museum-Related Events
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- General Sound Recordings of Museum-Related Activities, 1939-present
  - "Interview", November 19, 1994; PERSONALITY: Marcel Odenbach PLACE: The Video Study Center, The Museum of Modern Art SERIES: Video Program: Interviews by Barbara London PARTICIPANTS: Marcel Odenbach EXHIBITION:Video Spaces: Eight Installations[MoMA Exh. #1721, June 21(22)-September 12, 1995] DATA: Two 60-minute Standard Audio Cassettes RELATED MATERIAL: 94.43, 94.44, 94.47, 94.52, 95.24, 95.26 (Item 94.51a)
  - "Interview", November 19, 1994; PERSONALITY: Marcel Odenbach PLACE: The Video Study Center, The Museum of Modern Art SERIES: Video Program: Interviews by Barbara London PARTICIPANTS: Marcel Odenbach EXHIBITION:Video Spaces: Eight Installations[MoMA Exh. #1721, June 21(22)-September 12, 1995] DATA: Two 60-minute Standard Audio Cassettes RELATED MATERIAL: 94.43, 94.44, 94.47, 94.52, 95.24, 95.26 (Item 94.51b)
  - "Interview", November 19, 1994; PERSONALITY: Stan Douglas PLACE: The Video Study Center, The Museum of Modern Art SERIES: Video Program: Interviews by Barbara London PARTICIPANTS: Stan Douglas EXHIBITION:Video Spaces: Eight Installations[MoMA Exh. #1721, June 21(22)-September 12, 1995] DATA: Two 60-minute Standard Audio Cassettes RELATED MATERIAL: 94.43, 94.44, 94.47, 94.51a, 94.51b, 95.24, 95.26 (Item 94.52)
  - "Glenn Lowry, Museum of Modern Art", November 22, 1994; PERSONALITY: Glenn D. Lowry PARTICIPANTS: Glenn D. Lowry DATA: One Standard Audio Cassette, TRT: 3 minutes 15 seconds SUMMARY: WNYC-AM New York RELATED MATERIAL: 94.48, 94.49, 94.50, 95.4, 95.45 DONOR: Department of Public Information TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: 1994 (Item 94.53)
  - "Radcliffe Reception at The Museum of Modern Art in connection with American Politicians", December 9, 1994; PLACE: Sette MoMA PARTICIPANTS: Donna Hanover Giuliani; Barbara Nelson, Vice President, Radcliffe College; Susan Kismaric, Curator, Department of Photography, The Museum of Modern Art EXHIBITION:American Politicians: Photographs from 1943-1993[MoMA Exh. #1695, October 5, 1994-January 3, 1995] DATA: One 90-min Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: Introductions, Radcliffe's purpose, women in American life and politics, Susan Kismaric on the exhibition RELATED MATERIAL: 94.55a, 94.55b, 94.55aD, 94.55bD (Item 94.54)
  - "Visible/Invisible: Women In American Politics", Dec. 10, 1994; PARTICIPANTS: Barbara Nelson; Susan Kismaric, Curator, Department of Photography, The Museum of Modern Art; Carol Squiers, critic; A'lelia Bundtes; Esmeralda Santiago SPONSOR: The Museum of Modern Art and Radcliffe College, with the encouragement of Chemical Bank EXHIBITION:American Politicians: Photographs from 1943 to 1993( October 5, 1994-January 3, 1995) MoMA Exh. #1695 DATA: Two 90-minute Standard Audio Cassettes and two 30-minute cassettes; TRT( a and aD): 90 minutes; TRT (b and bD): 10 minutes SUMMARY: Symposium on representation of women in American politics. 5-minute talks by panelists, then group discussion. RELATED MATERIAL: 94.54 (Item 94.55a, 94.55 aD)
  - "Visible/Invisible: Women In American Politics", Dec. 10, 1994; PARTICIPANTS: Barbara Nelson; Susan Kismaric, Curator, Department of Photography, The Museum of Modern Art; Carol Squiers, critic; A'lelia Bundtes; Esmeralda Santiago SPONSOR: The Museum of Modern Art and Radcliffe College, with the encouragement of Chemical Bank EXHIBITION:American Politicians: Photographs from 1943 to 1993( October 5, 1994-January 3, 1995) MoMA Exh. #1695 DATA: Two 90-minute Standard Audio Cassettes and two 30-minute cassettes; TRT( a and aD): 90 minutes; TRT (b and bD): 10 minutes SUMMARY: Symposium on representation of women in American politics. 5-minute talks by panelists, then group discussion. RELATED MATERIAL: 94.54 (Item 94.55b, 94.55bD)
  - "Richard E. Oldenburg Farewell Dinner", December 21, 1994; PLACE: Four Seasons Restaurant, New York PARTICIPANTS: Louise Smith, The Museum of Modern Art Trustee; Robert Batterman, The Museum of Modern Art attorney; Barbara Jakobson, Christopher Mason (in song), Agnes Gund (long pause), Ronald Lauder, Paul Gottlieb, Mimi Gaudieri, Steingrim Laursen, Kirk Varnedoe, Chief Curator, Department of Painting and Sculpture, The Museum of Modern Art; Agnes Gund, Richard E. Oldenburg, Director, The Museum of Modern Art SPONSOR: Agnes Gund DATA: Two 90-minute Standard Audio Cassettes SUMMARY: Private dinner with remarks and musical tribute DONOR: Director's Office TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: September 13, 1996 (Item 94.56a)
  - "Richard E. Oldenburg Farewell Dinner", December 21, 1994; PLACE: Four Seasons Restaurant, New York PARTICIPANTS: Louise Smith, The Museum of Modern Art Trustee; Robert Batterman, The Museum of Modern Art attorney; Barbara Jakobson, Christopher Mason (in song), Agnes Gund (long pause), Ronald Lauder, Paul Gottlieb, Mimi Gaudieri, Steingrim Laursen, Kirk Varnedoe, Chief Curator, Department of Painting and Sculpture, The Museum of Modern Art; Agnes Gund, Richard E. Oldenburg, Director, The Museum of Modern Art SPONSOR: Agnes Gund DATA: Two 90-minute Standard Audio Cassettes; Duplicate is 1 90 Minute Standard Audio Cassette. Duplicate is of second portion of dinner only. SUMMARY: Private dinner with remarks and musical tribute DONOR: Director's Office TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: September 13, 1996; Duplicate arrived July 2004 (Item 94.56b, 94.56bD)
  - "Jacob Lawrence and Gwendolyn Knight Lawrence in Conversation with Henry Louis Gates, Jr.", January 13, 1995; PERSONALITY: Jacob Lawrence PLACE: The Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 1, The Museum of Modern Art PARTICIPANTS: Jacob Lawrence; Gwendolyn Knight Lawrence; Henry Louis Gates, Jr., W.E.B. du Bois Professor of the Humanities and Chairman of the Afro-American Studies Department, Harvard University SPONSOR: The Friends of Education EXHIBITION:Jacob Lawrence: The Migration Series[MoMA Exh. #1701, January 11(12)-April 11, 1995] DATA: Two 90-minute Standard Audio Cassettes, TRT: 80 minutes SUMMARY: Jacob Lawrence and Gwendolyn Knight Lawrence discuss their early experiences as artists RELATED MATERIAL: 95.2, 95.2D, 95.10, 95.12a and 95.12b, 95.12aD and 95.12bD DONOR: Department of Education TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: January 18, 1995; duplicate transferred October 18, 1996 (Item 95.1, 95.1D)
  - "Jacob Lawrence: The Migration Series", PERSONALITY: Jacob Lawrence EXHIBITION:Jacob Lawrence: The Migration Series[MoMA Exh. #1701, January 11(12)-April 11, 1995] SUMMARY: Promotional sound bite RELATED MATERIAL: 95.1, 95.1D, 95.10, 95.12a and 95.12b, 95.12aD and 95.12bD (Item 95.2, 95.2D)
  - "Kandinsky: Compositions Opening Dinner", Wednesday, January 25, 1995; PLACE: Sette MoMA PARTICIPANTS: Agnes Gund, President, The Museum of Modern Art; Glenn D. Lowry, Director, The Museum of Modern Art; Magdalena Dabrowski, Curator, Department of Drawings, The Museum of Modern Art SPONSOR: Robert Lehman Foundation, Inc.; National Endowment for the Arts; Federal Council on the Arts and the Humanities EXHIBITION:Kandinsky: Compositions[MoMA Exh. #1706, January 25(26)-April 25, 1995] DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette, TRT: 15 minutes DONOR: Department of Special Events (Item 95.3)
  - Untitled, February 8, 1995; PERSONALITY: Glenn D. Lowry PLACE: Garden Hall, The Museum of Modern Art PARTICIPANTS: Glenn D. Lowry DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: The director's welcome reception RELATED MATERIAL: 94.48, 94.49, 94.50, 94.53, 95.45 (Item 95.4)
  - "Dserts", February 10, 1995; PERSONALITY: Bill Viola PLACE: The Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 2, The Museum of Modern Art SERIES: Video Premieres PARTICIPANTS: Bill Viola SPONSOR: New York State Council on the Arts; Contemporary Arts Council, The Museum of Modern Art; Sony Corporation of America DATA: One 60-minute Standard Audio Cassette, TRT: 20 minutes SUMMARY: Introduction to the film by the filmmaker RELATED MATERIAL: 94.44 (Item 95.5)
  - "60th Anniversary of Architecture and Design at MoMA", February 15, 1995; PLACE: Sette MoMA PARTICIPANTS: Agnes Gund, President, The Museum of Modern Art; Glenn D. Lowry, Director, The Museum of Modern Art; Philip Johnson, artist DATA: One 60-minute Standard Audio Cassette, TRT: 20 minutes SUMMARY: Agnes Gund on Philip Johnson, Alfred H. Barr, Jr. and the Bauhaus,Machine Art catalogue reprinted for this benefit. Glenn D. Lowry introduces Stuart Wrede, Caroll McCarthy, Emilio Ambasz, Wilder Green, Peter Blake, Mildred Constantine, Ada Louise Huxtable. Philip Johnson on the earliest days of the department and philosophy of design. DONOR: Department of Special Events TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: February 17, 1995; NOTE: This sound recording was preserved in Spring, 2009 through a generous grant from The Museum of Modern Art Trustee Committee on Museum Archives, Library, and Research, in honor of Barbara Jakobson's Chairmanship. In addition to the original, a Broadcast Wave File (BWF) archival master, a DVD audio master, and a CD-R use copy now exist. (Item 95.6)
  - "Bruce Nauman Opening Dinner", March 1, 1995; PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art PARTICIPANTS: Agnes Gund, Chairman of the Board, The Museum of Modern Art; Glenn D. Lowry, Director, The Museum of Modern Art; Robert Storr, Curator of the exhibition and Curator, Department of Painting and Sculpture, The Museum of Modern Art EXHIBITION:Bruce Nauman[MoMA Exh. #1709, March 1(5)-May 23, 1995] DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: Opening dinner remarks RELATED MATERIAL: 95.17a and 95.17b, 95.17aD and 95.17bD (Item 95.7)
  - Untitled, March 3, 1995; PERSONALITY: Emma Amos PLACE: Edward John Noble Education Center and galleries, The Museum of Modern Art SERIES: Conversations with Contemporary Artists PARTICIPANTS: Emma Amos DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: Informal talk with the artist RELATED MATERIAL: 94.7, 94.10, 94.12, 94.15, 94.17, 94.18, 94.19, 94.20, 94.22, 94.24, 94.27, 94.36, 94.36D, 94.38, 94.38D, 94.40, 94.40D, 94.42, 94.42D, 94.45, 94.45D, 94.46, 94.46D, 95.11, 95.14, 95.15, 95.16 DONOR: Department of Education TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 18, 1996 (Item 95.8)
  - "Patrons Dinner", Wednesday, March 8, 1995; PLACE: Sette MoMA PARTICIPANTS: Speakers: Ralph Destino, Agnes Gund, President, The Museum of Modern Art; Glenn D. Lowry, Director, The Museum of Modern Art; Magdalena Dabrowski, Curator, Department of Drawings, The Museum of Modern Art SPONSOR: Hosted by Robert I. Smith Jr., Manager Corporate Relations, Department of Development, The Museum of Modern Art DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette (Item 95.9)
  - "Jacob Lawrence Keynote Lecture", Friday, March 10, 1995 8:00 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Mary Schmidt Campbell, Dean, Tisch School of the Arts, New York University PLACE: The Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 1, The Museum of Modern Art SPONSOR: In cooperation with the Graduate School and University Center of the City University of New York EXHIBITION:Jacob Lawrence: The Migration Series(January 11 - April 11, 1995) MoMA Exh. #1701 DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette, TRT: 55 minutes RELATED MATERIAL: 95.1, 95.1D, 95.2, 95.2D, 95.12a and 95.12b, 95.12aD and 95.12bD (Item 95.10)
  - Untitled, March 10, 1995; PERSONALITY: Mary Miss PLACE: Edward John Noble Education Center and galleries, The Museum of Modern Art SERIES: Conversations with Contemporary Artists PARTICIPANTS: Mary Miss DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: Informal talk with the artist RELATED MATERIAL: 94.7, 94.10, 94.12, 94.15, 94.17, 94.18, 94.19, 94.20, 94.22, 94.24, 94.27, 94.36, 94.36D, 94.38, 94.38D, 94.40, 94.40D, 94.42, 94.42D, 94.45, 94.45D, 94.46, 94.46D, 95.8, 95.14, 95.15, 95.16 DONOR: Department of Education TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 18, 1996 (Item 95.11)
  - "Jacob Lawrence Symposium - Panel Discussion", Saturday, March 11, 1995 8:00 p.m.; PLACE: The Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 1, The Museum of Modern Art PARTICIPANTS: Moderator: Michele Wallace, Professor, The City University of New York; Laura Rosenstock; Rose-Carol Washton Long; Patricia Hills, Professor of Art History, Boston University; Nicholas Lemann, author,The Promised Land; Bernice Johnson Reagon, Curator Emeritus, National Museum of American History SPONSOR: In cooperation with the Graduate School and University Center of the City University of New York EXHIBITION:Jacob Lawrence: The Migration Series[MoMA Exh. #1701, January 11(12)-April 11, 1995] DATA: Four 90-minute Standard Audio Cassettes, TRT (a and aD): 90 minutes and TRT (b and bD): 65 minutes SUMMARY: Panel Discussion of Jacob Lawrence's The Migration Series RELATED MATERIAL: 95.1, 95.1D, 95.2, 95.2D, 95.10, DONOR: Department of Education TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: March 17, 1995; duplicate transferred October 18, 1996 (Item 95.12a, 95.12aD)
  - "Jacob Lawrence Symposium - Panel Discussion", Saturday, March 11, 1995 8:00 p.m.; PLACE: The Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 1, The Museum of Modern Art PARTICIPANTS: Moderator: Michele Wallace, Professor, The City University of New York; Laura Rosenstock; Rose-Carol Washton Long; Patricia Hills, Professor of Art History, Boston University; Nicholas Lemann, author,The Promised Land; Bernice Johnson Reagon, Curator Emeritus, National Museum of American History SPONSOR: In cooperation with the Graduate School and University Center of the City University of New York EXHIBITION:Jacob Lawrence: The Migration Series[MoMA Exh. #1701, January 11(12)-April 11, 1995] DATA: Four 90-minute Standard Audio Cassettes, TRT (a and aD): 90 minutes and TRT (b and bD): 65 minutes SUMMARY: Panel Discussion of Jacob Lawrence's The Migration Series RELATED MATERIAL: 95.1, 95.1D, 95.2, 95.2D, 95.10, DONOR: Department of Education TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: March 17, 1995; duplicate transferred October 18, 1996 (Item 95.12b, 95.12bD)
  - "Frank Lloyd Wright's Presentation in Conceptual Drawings on CD-ROM", March 16, 1995; PARTICIPANTS: Peter Reed, Curator, Architecture & Design, The Museum of Modern Art; Ed Barry, Pres. Oxford University Press; Dick Signataro, VP Imaging, Kodak; Bruce Pfeiffer, Dir. FLW Archives; Michael Ester SPONSOR: Frank Lloyd Wright Foundation, Oxford U. Press, Luna Imaging, J. Paul Getty Trust DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette, TRT: 35 minutes SUMMARY: Launching and presentation of the CD-ROM as an electronic catalogue raisonne of 5,000 FLW drawings, with thanks to its authors and developers and a brief explanation of its creation. RELATED MATERIAL: 94.2, 94.2D (English version of Acoustiguide), 94.3, 94.3D (French version of Acoustiguide), 94.4, 94.4D (Spanish version of Acoustiguide), 94.5, 94.6, 94.8, 94.8D, 94.11a, 94.11b, 94.11aD, 94.11bD, 94.14, 94.16, 94.16D, 94.23a, 94.23b, 94.23c, 94.23d DONOR: Department of Architecture and Design (Item 95.13)
  - Untitled, March 17, 1995; PERSONALITY: Peter Forgacs PLACE: Edward John Noble Education Center and galleries, The Museum of Modern Art SERIES: Conversations with Contemporary Artists PARTICIPANTS: Peter Forgacs DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: Informal talk with the artist RELATED MATERIAL: 94.7, 94.10, 94.12, 94.15, 94.17, 94.18, 94.19, 94.20, 94.22, 94.24, 94.27, 94.36, 94.36D, 94.38, 94.38D, 94.40, 94.40D, 94.42, 94.42D, 94.45, 94.45D, 94.46, 94.46D, 95.8, 95.11, 95.15, 95.16 DONOR: Department of Education TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 18, 1996 (Item 95.14)
  - Untitled, March 24, 1995; PERSONALITY: Polly Apfelbaum PLACE: Edward John Noble Education Center and galleries, The Museum of Modern Art SERIES: Conversations with Contemporary Artists PARTICIPANTS: Polly Apfelbaum DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: Informal talk with the artist RELATED MATERIAL: 94.7, 94.10, 94.12, 94.15, 94.17, 94.18, 94.19, 94.20, 94.22, 94.24, 94.27, 94.36, 94.36D, 94.38, 94.38D, 94.40, 94.40D, 94.42, 94.42D, 94.45, 94.45D, 94.46, 94.46D, 95.8, 95.11, 95.14, 95.16 DONOR: Department of Education TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 18, 1996 (Item 95.15)
  - Untitled, March 31, 1995; PERSONALITY: Edin Velez PLACE: Edward John Noble Education Center and galleries, The Museum of Modern Art SERIES: Conversations with Contemporary Artists PARTICIPANTS: Edin Velez DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: Informal talk with the artist RELATED MATERIAL: 94.7, 94.10, 94.12, 94.15, 94.17, 94.18, 94.19, 94.20, 94.22, 94.24, 94.27, 94.36, 94.36D, 94.38, 94.38D, 94.40, 94.40D, 94.42, 94.42D, 94.45, 94.45D, 94.46, 94.46D, 95.8, 95.11, 95.14, 95.15 DONOR: Department of Education TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 18, 1996 (Item 95.16)
  - "Bruce Nauman: Idea into Image", Tuesday, April 11, 1995 7:00 pm; PLACE: The Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 2, The Museum of Modern Art PARTICIPANTS: Moderated by Robert Storr, Curator, Department of Painting and Sculpture, The Museum of Modern Art; Joan Acocella, dance critic and author of Mark Morris; Peter Plagens, painter, art critic for Newsweek and longtime contributer to Art in America; Peter Schjeldahl, art critic The Village Voice and author,Columns and Catalogues(The Figures, 1994). EXHIBITION:Bruce Nauman[MoMA Exh. #1709, March 1(5)-May 23, 1995] DATA: Two 120-minutes Standard Audio Cassettes, one 90-minute, one 30 -minute cassette: TRT (a and aD): 90:00; TRT ( b and bD): 14:00 SUMMARY: Panel discussion moderated by Robert Storr, Curator, Department of Painting and Scultpure, The Museum of Modern Art RELATED MATERIAL: 95.7 TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: April 14, 1995; duplicates transferred October 18, 1996 (Item 95.17a, 95.17aD)
  - "Bruce Nauman: Idea into Image", Tuesday, April 11, 1995 7:00 pm; PLACE: The Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 2, The Museum of Modern Art PARTICIPANTS: Moderated by Robert Storr, Curator, Department of Painting and Sculpture, The Museum of Modern Art; Joan Acocella, dance critic and author of Mark Morris; Peter Plagens, painter, art critic for Newsweek and longtime contributer to Art in America; Peter Schjeldahl, art critic The Village Voice and author,Columns and Catalogues(The Figures, 1994). EXHIBITION:Bruce Nauman[MoMA Exh. #1709, March 1(5)-May 23, 1995] DATA: Two 120-minutes Standard Audio Cassettes, one 90-minute, one 30 -minute cassette: TRT (a and aD): 90:00; TRT ( b and bD): 14:00 SUMMARY: Panel discussion moderated by Robert Storr, Curator, Department of Painting and Scultpure, The Museum of Modern Art RELATED MATERIAL: 95.7 TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: April 14, 1995; duplicates transferred October 18, 1996 (Item 95.17 b, 95.17bD)
  - "La Biennale De Venezia Press Conference", April 26, 1995; PLACE: Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Sculpture Garden, The Museum of Modern Art PARTICIPANTS: Agnes Gund, President, The Museum of Modern Art; Glenn D. Lowry, Director, The Museum of Modern Art; Gianluigi Gabetti, The Museum of Modern Art Trustee; Gerard Regnier; question and answer period DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette DONOR: Director's Office TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: September 13, 1996 (Item 95.18)
  - "Louise Reinhardt Smith Exhibition Opening Dinner", May 3, 1995; PLACE: Sette MoMA PARTICIPANTS: Agnes Gund, President, The Museum of Modern Art; Glenn D. Lowry, Director, The Museum of Modern Art; William Rubin, Director Emeritus, Department of Painting and Sculpture, The Museum of Modern Art; Richard E. Oldenburg, Director Emeritus, The Museum of Modern Art; Kirk Varnedoe, Chief Curator, Department of Painting and Sculpture, The Museum of Modern Art; Dorothy Cullman, Agnes Gund, Louise Smith, Lewis Cullman, W. Rubin, R. Oldenburg, A. Gund SPONSOR: Dorothy and Lewis Cullman EXHIBITION:Masterworks from the Louise Reinhardt Smith Collection[MoMA Exh. #1712, May 3(4)-August 22, 1995] DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette DONOR: Director's Office TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: September 13, 1996 (Item 95.19)
  - "Ink-Stained Wretch: A Conversation with Christopher Knight on Journalism, Criticism and Art", Monday, May 22, 1995 8:00 p.m.; PERSONALITY: Christopher Knight PLACE: The Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 2, The Museum of Modern Art PARTICIPANTS: Christopher Knight, art critic,Los Angeles Times; author,Last Chance for Eden: Selected Art Criticism, 1979-1994 SPONSOR: Lannan Foundation DATA: Two 90-minute Standard Audio Cassettes SUMMARY: Christopher Knight speaks on his published work, on journalistic art criticism in general, and on the state of contemporary art. RELATED MATERIAL: 95.20D TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: Duplicate transferred October 18, 1996 (Item 95.20, 95.20D)
  - "Mutant Materials in Contemporary Art Opening Dinner", Wednesday, May 24, 1995; PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art PARTICIPANTS: Agnes Gund, President, The Museum of Modern Art; Terence Riley, Chief Curator, Department of Architecture and Design, The Museum of Modern Art; Paola Antonelli, Associate Curator, Department of Architecture and Design, The Museum of Modern Art EXHIBITION:Mutant Materials in Contemporary Art(May 24 - Aug. 27, 1995) MoMA Exh. #1713 DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette, TRT: 10 minutes (Item 95.21)
  - "Party in the Garden Dinner Remarks", June 5, 1995; PLACE: Sette MoMA SERIES: Annual Spring Benefit PARTICIPANTS: Agnes Gund, President, The Museum of Modern Art; Mary Lea Bandy, Curator, Department of Film and Video, The Museum of Modern Art; Celeste Bartos; David Rockefeller; Glenn D. Lowry, Director, The Museum of Modern Art; Gerald Lavin SUMMARY: Dinner remarks RELATED MATERIAL: 93.11b, 94.32 DONOR: Joan Howard, Special Events TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: June, 1995 (Item 95.22)
  - Untitled, June 14, 1995; PERSONALITY: Riva Castleman PLACE: Garden, Garden Hall, The Museum of Modern Art PARTICIPANTS: Glenn D. Lowry, Director, The Museum of Modern Art; Ronald Lauder, Chairman of the Board, The Museum of Modern Art; Agnes Gund, President, The Museum of Modern Art; Walter Bareiss,Trustee, The Museum of Modern Art; William Goldstein, ULAE; Deborah Wye, Curator, Department of Prints and Illustrated Books, The Museum of Modern Art DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: Reception in honor of Riva Castleman upon her retirement TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: 1995 (Item 95.23)
  - Untitled, June 23, 1995 6:30 pm.; PERSONALITY: Teiji Furuhashi PLACE: Edward John Noble Education Center and galleries, The Museum of Modern Art SERIES: Artist Talks PARTICIPANTS: Teiji Furuhashi EXHIBITION:Video Spaces: Eight Installations[MoMA Exh. #1721, June 21(22)-September 12, 1995] DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: Informal lecture by artists featured in the exhibition speaking about their individual bodies of work. RELATED MATERIAL: 94.43, 94.44, 94.47, 94.51a, 94.51b, 94.52, 95.26 DONOR: Department of Education TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 18, 1996 (Item 95.24)
  - "Artist's Choice: Elizabeth Murray", June 26, 1995 8:15 p.m.; PLACE: The Roy and Niuta Titus Theater I, The Museum of Modern Art SERIES: Artist's Choice PARTICIPANTS: Linda Nochlin, Professor of Modern Art, Institute of Fine Art, NYU; Marcia Tucker, Director, The New Museum of Contemporary Art, Jennifer Bartlett, artist EXHIBITION:Artist's Choice: Elizabeth Murray(June 19 - August 22, 1995) MoMA Exh.#1720 DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: The panel discusses issues, including feminist concerns, raised by the Artist's Choice exhibition. DONOR: Department of Education TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 18, 1996 (Item 95.25)
  - Untitled, June 29 ,1995 6:30 pm.; PERSONALITY: Tony Oursler PLACE: Edward John Noble Education Center and galleries, The Museum of Modern Art SERIES: Artist Talks PARTICIPANTS: Tony Oursler EXHIBITION:Video Spaces: Eight Installations[MoMA Exh. #1721, June 21(22)-September 12, 1995] DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: Informal lecture by artists featured in the exhibition who speak about their individual bodies of work. RELATED MATERIAL: 94.43, 94.44, 94.47, 94.51a, 94.51b, 94.52, 95.24 DONOR: Department of Education TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 18, 1996 (Item 95.26)